# AWAN APRILINO

Desa Mlatirejo RT 02 RW 04, Kecamatan Bulu, Kabupaten Rembang, Jawa Tengah · 6285156052586 aprilinoawan@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/awanaprilino · awaaan.com

Entry-level Backend Developer with 2 years of experience designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases. My skills might be limited, but my desire to learn new things and develop professionally are endless.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### **APRIL 2021 - MARCH 2023**

## **BACKEND DEVELOPER, REFOURMA**

- Design robust APIs to support mobile and web clients
- Optimize web applications for performance and scalability
- Write code and tests, resolve issues, and profile and analyze bottlenecks
- Fix bugs and improve existing systems.
- Create and maintain workflows with teams to provide visibility and to ensure workload balance for consistent visual designs
- Develop and oversee testing schedules in client server environment, addressing various browsers and devices to ensure that content is displayed as intended
- Produce quality code, raise the bar for team performance and speed
- Maintain workflows with client teams to ensure ongoing support, along with leading training and mentorship for junior developers.

#### **JANUARY 2021 - MARCH 2021**

# WEB DEVELOPER (INTERN), PT. ENERGI BANGSA SOLUSINDO

- Create web system based on client request
- Design APIs to support mobile clients

## **EDUCATION**

**AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2022** 

## **BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, UNIVERSITAS STIKUBANK SEMARANG**

Major: Computer Science (3.82 Major GPA)

# **SKILLS**

- Proficient: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreeSQL, Laravel, NodeJs, GIT, REST API.
- Familiar: ReactJS, Python, RabbitMQ, GCP, Linux Commands, AWS, MongoDB.